# Nalini Agrawal

1301 N Troy St, #403
Arlington, VA 22201
434.466.0950
naliniagrawal@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Ambitious and accomplished analytics consultant with 4+ years of experience developing analytical solutions to solve business problems for several major clients in various industries. Depended on as a key person to build multivariate models, develop data visualizations, conduct in-depth analysis and provide actionable results to leadership.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Deloitte Consulting LLP, Washington, DC

June 2020 - Present

Senior Consultant

- Led and performed data mining, data cleaning, and machine learning modeling to determine the number of medical records that are submitted for a large federal healthcare organization using SAS and Python
- Ideated and developed a new modeling pipeline that simulates changes in the operational process of auditing medical records
- Led the analytics workstream for a large health services company, built a repeatable process using SQL and Excel to refresh and maintain the asset inventory of ~30k technology assets which led to the creation of executive dashboards for client leadership

Consultant June 2018 – June 2020

- Improved the analytics infrastructure for one of the largest multinational pharmaceutical companies by developing a version control and standardization methodology after conducting extensive stakeholder interviews. Used by ~250 data scientists at the organization, the methodology drove improved productively, traceability and auditability of the analytics performed at the organization
- Instrumental in the development of a Deloitte workforce analytics product. Validated extensive python code, statistical models, conducted interviews with the business which led to the creation of a product with ~\$8M pipeline
- Created an automated dashboard using Excel VBA that was used to deliver 10 client projects
- Developed risk-adjusted models using SAS and SQL for a large state's Department of Health for 2 Medicaid programs comprising of 120k members across 13 health plans with ~10M claims. The models led to appropriate allocations of capitation payments based on the risk profile of the members
- Led the onsite team at an insurance client and built a customized algorithmic solution in SAS to help a long-term disability insurance client better understand the Loss Ratio projections of its large case LTD block. The solution led to improved risk selection, underwriting action, and pricing through improved segmentation

Business Analyst August 2016 – June 2018

- Analyzed 18M files deemed as potential technologies relevant to upcoming technology transformation program. Created automated Python and VBA based scripts to comprehensively catalog all files based on their capabilities, complexity, and relevance which decreased program timeline by 30%
- Monitored and maintained 350k client accounts in SQL on a sensitive project which led to the corrected assignment of interest rate conditions for all clients
- Built a regression model in SAS for educational non-profit and identified factors that improved mentor-mentee relationship

## OmniTek Consulting, McLean, VA

September 2013 – July 2014

Management and Technology consulting company focused on the healthcare sector *Business Analyst* 

- Developed business requirement specifications and system design documents to prepare for required system enhancements
- Managed system production support after 2 major upgrades resulting in smooth implementation
- Supported multiple client initiatives to meet aggressive timelines while addressing critical business solutions

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Texas**, Austin, TX

May 2016

MS, Business Analytics

**University of Virginia**, Charlottesville, VA BS, Commerce, Minor in Economics

May 2013

## **SKILLS**

- Languages: English (Fluent; oral and written), Hindi (Native; oral and written)
- Technical Languages: Python, SAS, SQL, Tableau, Power BI, Excel VBA
- Other: reporting, forecasting, data analytics, data visualization, project management, strategic communications, technical writing, stakeholder management, executive briefings, training

<b>Industry and Sector Experience</b> Real Estate, Insurance	s: Financial Services,	Banking, Healthcar	re, Public Sector, Co	onsumer Products, To	eleco